psoriasis.org 2019-08-27

# Privacy Policy | National Psoriasis Foundation

The National Psoriasis Foundation (NPF) respects the privacy of each individual who contacts us. We are grateful for your support and the critical role you play in helping us continue our valuable work. To protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our information practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used.

### Collection and Use of Data

In order to provide our users the best experience possible on our website, we collect information about visitors to our site, such as the number of visitors, what pages they access and the length of their visit. This type of information is shared outside the National Psoriasis Foundation only as compiled data and no information that can identify any one individual.

We collect information such as your name, postal address and e-mail address when you choose to share that information. Examples include: when you request information from us, register for an event, make a donation or contact us offline. This information is used to provide you with information or deliver the materials you have requested. If you provide your postal or e-mail address to the National Psoriasis Foundation, you will receive postal and e-mail communications from us. We also collect demographic and profile data at our site and in our databases. We use the data you provide to tailor your experience on our website and develop programs and services that might be of interest to you.

### Opting Out of Communications

We send out electronic and other communications to National Psoriasis Foundation constituents to highlight news, information and opportunities available from the National Psoriasis Foundation. You can elect not to receive communications from us, either by updating the communications preferences or by contacting us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#8ee9ebfae7e0e8e1cefefde1fce7effde7fda0e1fce9). In addition, all National Psoriasis Foundation e-mail communications have easy-to-follow unsubscribe instructions at the bottom of each e-mail.

### Use of Cookies

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your web browser on your computer's hard drive. The National Psoriasis Foundation website uses cookies to verify forms and to enable users with online accounts to use the "Remember Login" option to have their login information automatically saved for them. Consult the help menu on your web browser regarding options for preventing or accepting cookies. Please be aware that if you block cookies, some of our website functions may not be available to you.

### Sharing Information with Others

The National Psoriasis Foundation, like many other nonprofit organizations, occasionally makes available only our constituents' names and postal addresses to companies, predominantly other nonprofit organizations. We carefully screen these organizations. These practices help us reduce the cost of reaching more individuals with information about psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis.

You can request that we do not share your information by e-mailing us at [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#d4b3b1a0bdbab2bb94a4a7bba6bdb5a7bda7fabba6b3). If you use more than one e-mail address or postal address, please identify each one.

We will also share such personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our rights, or protect the safety of our constituents or others.

### Children's Privacy Online

National Psoriasis Foundation produces websites, including, PsoMe.org, as well as the "Youth" section of NPF's website (collectively, hereinafter, "Website,"), that are intended for use by children, including those under the age of thirteen. Protecting the privacy of children is especially important, and for this reason we have adopted certain policies and procedures to help do so.

> 1\. The Information We Collect  
> As described in this Privacy Policy, we directly collect personally identifiable information from a child when a user submits a form through our Website. This information may include the child's name, age, email address, gender, address and country of residence. We may also request a user name and email address so that we may respond to an inquiry.
> 
> NPF uses personally identifiable information to help provide the most appropriate and thorough answers to questions. For example, NPF may use an email address to seek more detailed information in order to answer a submitted question or to provide a private answer to a question. Typically, NPF will not condition the child's participation in any activity on the Website on the disclosure of any more information than is reasonably necessary to participate.
> 
> Additionally, when visitors come to our site, we may passively collect certain non-personally identifiable computer information. This information may include the user's: type of computer operating system (e.g., Windows 7 or Mac OS X Snow Leopard), the user's IP Address, the user's web browser (e.g., Mozilla Firefox or Internet Explorer), the frequency with which users visit various parts of our sites, and information regarding the user's Internet service provider. We do this in order to make our sites more interesting and useful to you and for various purposes related to NPF. We may collect this non-personally identifiable information through the use of software technologies such as unique identifiers or "cookies." Cookies are small text files that we place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. You can choose to have your computer warn you each time a cookie is sent, or you can choose to "turn off" the acceptance of cookies from any website. If you turn cookies off, you won't have access to many features that make your Web experience smoother, and some of our services may not function properly.
> 
> 2\. How We Use, Disclose, and Store the Information We Collect  
> In addition to the purposes described in Section 1, we may actively collect and use personally identifiable information to track usage and to ensure users are following the site's Terms of Use. In addition, we may use personally identifiable information to ban a user temporarily or permanently from the Website if that user engages in inappropriate conduct on the site.
> 
> We may disclose information where we are required to do so by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena, or for other judicial process. We may also disclose information reasonably necessary to protect the safety of a child or a participant on this Website. We may disclose information to service providers or other affiliated companies who provide support for the operations of our website and who we believe do not use or disclose the information for any other purpose. To the extent permitted by applicable law, we also may disclose personally identifiable information in response to a law enforcement agency's or other public agencies (including schools or children services) request or if we feel that such disclosure may prevent the instigation of a crime, facilitate an investigation related to public safety or protect the safety of a child using our website, to protect the security or integrity of our website, or enable us to take precautions against liability. When possible, we will use reasonable methods of providing parents notice of this disclosure.
> 
> 3\. Collection of Information for Third-Party Sites and Sponsors  
> Information about children is not collected for marketing purposes, and it is not disclosed to third parties. Nor do we allow third-party companies to advertise to our users. We intend to keep this site free from direct advertising.
> 
> 4\. Security  
> We have established and maintain reasonable procedures to protect the confidentiality, security, and integrity of personal information collected from children.
> 
> 5\. Contact Us  
> If you have questions or wish to send us comments about this Privacy Policy, please send an e-mail with your questions or comments to [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#8ce7e5e8ffccfcffe3fee5edffe5ffa2e3feeb) or write us:
>
>> **PsoMe**  
>  c/o National Psoriasis Foundation  
> Attention: Outreach Department  
> 6600 SW 92nd Ave., Suite 300  
> Portland, OR 97223-7195  
> USA
> 
> When contacting us, please be sure to provide us with your e-mail address and a telephone number where we can reach you.
> 
> Unless you so request, any personal information that you provide in communications to the above e-mail and postal mail addresses will not be used to send you promotional materials.

### TalkPsoriasis.org Online Community

The TalkPsoriasis online community is sponsored by the National Psoriasis Foundation and hosted by Inspire. Individuals who register on [TalkPsoriasis.org](http://www.talkpsoriasis.org/) agree to the privacy policy set forth by Inspire. [More information on the Inspire privacy policy](http://www.inspire.com/about/privacy).

The National Psoriasis Foundation does not endorse or accept any responsibility for the content of external websites. For more information see our complete terms of use.

### Security

In order to prevent unauthorized access and protect our users' personal information, we strive to maintain physical, electronic and administrative safeguards to secure the information we collect online. For example, online shopping and contributions are processed using a secure server. This secure server software, SSL (Secure Sockets Layer), encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. Furthermore, all of the customer data we collect is protected against unauthorized access with the use of digital certificates.

### Links to Other Sites

Our site provides links to other websites where you can find out more about our partners, other organizations, or products and services related to psoriasis and psoriatic arthritis. Please note that the National Psoriasis Foundation is not responsible for the information practices of linked sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of each site you visit.

### Privacy Policy Changes

The privacy policy set out above is effective as of February 5, 2011, and applies to all information previously obtained by NPF. We reserve the right to change the privacy policy at our sole discretion. Changes to the National Psoriasis Foundation privacy policy will be posted on our website. We encourage you to review our policy from time to time.

### Questions or Concerns

The National Psoriasis Foundation welcomes your questions and comments about this privacy statement, about the practices of the National Psoriasis Foundation, and about your experiences with this website. To contact us with questions about our privacy policy:

**National Psoriasis Foundation**  
6600 SW 92nd Ave., Suite 300  
Portland, OR 97223-7195  
Phone: 503.244.7404 or 800.723.9166  
Fax: 503.245.0626  
Email: [[email protected]](https://web.archive.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#620507160b0c040d2212110d100b03110b114c0d1005)

Our regular business hours are Monday through Friday, 8:00 a.m. to 5:00 p.m. Pacific Time.

Approved by the Board of Trustees February 5, 2011
